人人影視
YYeTs.com
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯： 暴龍蛋     圈圈     阿髻     胖兔純
翻譯： 蘇小黛     Kiko     DustD
時間軸： 濃子   芝麻圓子    校對： 蘇小黛   胖兔純
后期： 孤帆    總監： 米小勒   胖兔純
塞勒姆
第一季  第四集
《塞勒姆》前情提要
Previously on "Salem"
感謝你多年來對我們的英勇守護
We all welcome Captain Alden home
歡迎回家  奧登上尉
from his long, long service.
你回來的目的只有一個
You come back for one thing and one thing only.
如今她可是瑪麗·西布里
She's Mary Sibley now.
我一直在等著你
I waited for you.
年復一年  你卻杳無音訊
Years and years without a word.
我被俘虜了
I was captured.
或許我們可以忘了塞勒姆和這些巫師們
If we could forget Salem and its witches.
去過不同的生活
If we could have a different life.
她不能呼吸了
She can't breathe!
求求你  住手吧
Make it stop.
求你放過我女兒
Please. My daughter.
我們稱此為魔鬼侵襲...
We call it a spectral attack --
是巫師所為
The work of witches.
為她祈禱吧
Pray for her.
圣子在命令你...[拉丁文]
Imperat tibi Deus Filius...
圣靈在命令你...[拉丁文]
Imperat tibi Deus Spiritus Sanctus...
造物之主耶穌...[拉丁文]
Imperat tibi majestas Christi...
住手
You must stop this.
基督命令你...[拉丁文]
aeternum Dei Verbum caro factum...
圣十字架命令你...[拉丁文]
Imperat sacramentum crucis...
要是他們知道了  你會被絞死的
They will hang you if they learn of this.
巫師們已經奪走了你的人生
The witches have already taken your life.
我不怕那些清教徒會怎么對我
I no longer fear the puritans claiming mine.
你體內那污穢的靈魂必須被驅逐
The wretched spirit that inhabits you must be excised.
不然你知道會有什么下場嗎
Or else what becomes of you?
發瘋
Hmm? Madness?
死亡
Death?
你相信我嗎  梅西
Do you trust me, Mercy?
是的  父親
Yes, father.
相信我不會傷害你  對嗎
That I would do nothing to hurt you?
當然
Well, of course.
父親  父親
Father. Father.
我要清除你體內每一片不潔的靈魂...
I cast you out, every unclean spirit...
每一點魔鬼的力量...
every satanic power...
不要  我求你
Please! I beseech you!
每一次
Every onslaught
邪惡敵人的猛攻...
of the infernal adversary...
以我主基督之手  以我主基督之名
In the name and in the power of our Lord Jesus.
你才是真正瘋了
It's you that's been driven to madness!
是巫術
Malleus maleficarum.
*擂我戰鼓*
*Pound me the witch drums*
*鼓鳴震天*
*Witch drums*
*擂我戰鼓*
*Pound me the witch drums*
*鼓鳴震天*
*The witch drums*
*寧入地獄*
*Better pray for hell*
*不留人間*
*Not hallelujah*
《塞勒姆》  第一季第四集
早上好
Good morning.
剛來的那艘船上有我的一個包裹
I, uh, am here to collect a parcel incoming on that vessel.
流感爆發了
Influenza outbreak.
死了五個人
Five dead.
那艘船被隔離了
Frigate's under quarantine.
隔離
Quarantine?
誰下的令
By whose order?
喬治·西布里
George Sibley.
是他妻子瑪麗·西布里代為下令的
By way of his wife, Mary Sibley.
你們男人會渴望
Does a man desire
知道自己什么時候會歸天嗎
to know when he is on the precipice of his own death?
喬治  你說...
What say you, George?
你那個鐵匠朋友
Would your friend, the blacksmith,
會想知道還有多久
want to know that scant hours from now,
梅西·路易絲就會控告他巫師罪嗎
Mercy Lewis will accuse him of witchcraft?
然后他的審判和處決就將接踵而來
From which his trial and execution will swiftly follow?
還是他更想
Or would he favor
毫不知情地度過這所剩無多的時間
his waning moments be spent in ignorance?
別為他難過  喬治
Oh, don't pity him, George.
正是你這些無辜朋友的血
It is the blood of innocents like your friend
才讓我們的大祭典成為可能
that make our grand rite possible.
每一次控告和審判
Each accusation made,
都不是針對我們  而是由我們掌控的
each trial convened not for us, but by us.
沒人會想到我們的計劃
No one the wiser to our plan
也沒人膽敢阻止我們的腳步
and nobody brave enough to stand in our way.
你想念他們  對吧
You miss them, don't you?
我小時候
When I was young,
一直認為他們都是壞人
I thought them horribly sensible people.
但現在...
Now...
塞勒姆缺的正是他們
Salem could use more like them.
抱歉打擾了  上尉
I'm intruding, captain.
不  不
No, no.
很高興你還活著
I'm glad you're amongst the living...
恕我直言
So to speak.
我聽說你病的不輕
Word was you had taken quite ill.
確實如此
Indeed.
不知為何  我突然就發作了
A fit that came on suddenly and without reason,
睡也睡不安穩
followed by a restless sleep
那疾病似乎感染了我的夢境
in which the sickness infected even my dreams.
你的夢境
Your dreams?
我夢到一只沒有眼白的玩偶
I dreamt of a doll with eyes full and black.
我半夜醒來  渾身高熱
And when I awoke, feverish in the night's middle,
我發誓那只玩偶也在那盯著我
I could have sworn the doll was there, staring back at me.
高熱會使你產生幻覺
Fever dreams can be quite vivid.
但我發誓
Except I could have sworn
我看到我父親走入了黑暗之中
that I saw my father enter in darkness
拿走了那只玩偶
and remove the doll.
但只要我一提起  他就笑著跟我說...
But when I asked, he laughed and assured me that...
你是在做夢
You were dreaming.
你也覺得不可信對嗎  奧登上尉
Do you doubt my father's veracity, Captain Alden?
不
No.
但這似乎你是這么想的
But it seems like you do.
我...
I...
毫無疑問他是個好人
I have no doubt that he's a good man.
但最近...
But lately...
什么
What?
早知道你跟他在一起
Had I but known you were in such safe hands,
你母親就不用那么擔心了
I would have spared your mother her worry.
治安官
Magistrate.
走吧  安
Come along, Anne.
不要打擾奧登上尉了
Let us allow captain Alden his privacy.
我沒聽錯吧
Have I heard you correctly?
你是說安·霍爾是受害者  她被...
Are you suggesting that Anne Hale is the victim of...
下咒了
A spell.
我也被下咒了嗎
Am I, too, the victim of a spell?
還是約翰·奧登終于相信有巫師存在了
Or has John Alden finally declared his belief in witches?
我親眼所見太多證據  無法否認了
I've seen too much to deny any longer,
所以很明顯我下一步...要抓一個巫師
making my next step obvious...catching one.
你也知道  抓捕巫師不是件容易的事
As you know, apprehending a witch is no easy feat.
只要知道他們是誰就不難
Unless you know who they are.
你找到給安下咒的巫師了嗎
Have you uncovered the conjurer who spelled Anne?
是誰
Who is it?
告訴我
Tell me.
一個與受害者很親近的人
Someone in proximity to his victim.
對
Yes.
他自己的女兒也說出了自己的懷疑
Whose own daughter voices her suspicions.
霍爾治安官嗎
Magistrate Hale?
他不是大家所想的那樣
He's not who he seems.
我們之中誰是
Who amongst us is?
你嗎
You?
還是我
Or I?
我們當中誰沒有
Who among us is unburdened by shame
不為人知的恥辱或者秘密
or secrets that we hide from the world?
我是麥哲牧師
I'm Reverend Mather.
你有問題嗎
Is there a problem?
沒有
Well, no.
這位女士剛跟我談生意呢
The lady and I were just discussing some business.
-生意  -對
- Business? - Yes.
比如我要花多少錢才能...
As in how much it might cost me to get down to some...
這里是個受人尊敬的地方
This is a reputable establishment!
不許你在這里縱欲淫蕩
It offers no place for your lechery.
-牧師  -牧師
- Reverend. - Reverend.
柯頓
Cotton!
不好意思
Pardon me.
如有冒犯  我在此道歉
I apologize if I've caused any offense.
日安
Good day.
你認識那人嗎
Do you know that man?
從未見過
Never seen him before.
玫瑰花環
Ring around the rosies
花束千萬
Pocketful of posies
灰燼飄落
Ashes, ashes
人死歸天
We all fall down
不錯
Ah, Yeah.
她來了
She has arrived.
梅西
Mercy.
親愛的  真是上帝保佑
My dear, this is a blessing.
確實
Truly.
她終于有機會再次呼吸秋天的新鮮空氣了
And she is again well enough to breathe the fall air.
曾經越是理所當然之事
Our deepest gratitude is often saved
才越需要我們無盡的感激
for what we once took for granted.
梅西
Mercy?
-怎么了  -不
- What is it? - No.
孩子  不要  不要
No, my child. No. No.
巫師
The witch!!
巫師是誰  梅西
Who's the witch, Mercy?
告訴我們  誰是巫師
Tell us! Who's the witch?!
他是巫師嗎  梅西
Is he the witch, Mercy?
是他嗎
Is he?
梅西
Mercy?
Mercy!
快來幫忙
Help!
快來人幫忙
Will someone help us?!
怎么回事
What's happened?
我們失去控制了
We've lost control.
她不再是我們的人了
She is no longer ours.
大家躁動不安
The hive is restless.
有人甚至開始懷疑你的計劃是否利于我們
Some are beginning to doubt your grand vision for our kind.
是誰  告訴我名字
Who? Give me their names.
這不是重點  孩子
You're missing the point, child.
那他也許該告訴我重點
Then perhaps he should make one.
審判是以指控為前提的
Trials are preceded by accusations.
而指控是否成功則取決于你對那女孩的控制
And accusations are predicated upon your control of the girl.
狩獵月很快就要到了
The hunter's moon fast approaches.
而那個鐵匠
Yet the blacksmith
還在盡情兜售自己的鐵器
still blithely peddles his wares,
他應該為我們的事業犧牲
his blood lost to our cause.
豈有此理
How dare you.
瑪麗未加入之前
Before Mary,
不是眾人怕我們  而是我們擔驚受怕
we were not feared, but fearful,
我們不是獵人  而是獵物
not hunters, but prey.
可她的力量和計劃得到你的一點贊揚了嗎
And yet does her strength and vision garner your praise?
沒有
No.
只有你的懷疑
Only your doubt.
那個女孩只是因為身體狀況而日趨虛弱
The girl has been rendered frail by her circumstance.
僅此而已
Nothing more.
我對她的控制沒有問題
My mastery is not of issue.
這是你的保證嗎
This is an assurance?
她只是需要休息一段時間
She needs but a moment of rest.
之后  她就會恢復力量
After which, she will again be strong enough
去指認他人
to point the finger.
還有個問題沒有解決...
Yet another issue remains...
約翰·奧登
That of John Alden.
他怎么了
What of him?
他明顯在懷疑我
His suspicion of me is palpable.
如果她無法解除威脅
If she cannot abate his threat,
那我會親自動手  這并無不妥吧
then I will be forced to do so myself -- as I see fit.
如果你想得到約翰·奧登的信任
Should you desire John Alden's trust,
我建議你想辦法去自己爭取
I would suggest you find a way to earn it.
至于  瑪麗
And, Mary...
你的的目標指引著我們
Your vision guides us.
我會向其他人報告
I will report to the others
你的計劃將繼續進行
that your plan shall resume anon.
我們需要盡快找到答案
We need answers quickly.
我們會找到的
And we will get them.
怎么找
How?
找到答案的最快方法
The quickest way one finds answers...
就是指責
blame.
你是想要抹殺我對你
Is it your intent to rob me
僅存的信心了嗎  牧師
of my remaining faith in you, reverend?
西布里夫人  我沒注意到您來了
Mrs. Sibley. I didn't hear you arrive.
你的職責  簡單明了
Your charge, simple and clear,
就是要保護路易絲不再被惡魔附身
is to protect the Lewis girl from further possession.
然而  在集市里發生的那一幕
And yet...was the episode in the marketplace
不正表明這又重演了嗎
not evidence of exactly that?
沒有證據表明這是巫師所為
We have no proof it was the work of witches.
這么說你已經去看過她了
So you've paid her a visit, then?
你知道是什么在折磨她了嗎
You've determined what ails her?
牧師說她正在休息
The pastor says she's resting
最好不被打擾
and best not be disturbed.
我能問你個問題嗎  牧師
May I ask you a question, reverend?
你的父親搜尋魔鬼之時  他請求許可了嗎
When your father seeks out demons, does he ask permission?
他會禮貌敲門
Does he knock on doors
并答應等到方便的時候再來拜訪嗎
and offer to come back at a more convenient time?
還是他秉持著上帝的正義
Or does he, armed with the Lord's righteousness,
命令魔鬼給他回應
demand the demon answer to him?
父親和我截然不同
My father and I are different men.
我們有不同的工作方式
We work in different ways.
當我傳召獵人追捕巫師
When I summoned a hunter of witches
從而保護塞勒姆的人民時  我要找的人并不是你
to protect the people of Salem, it was not you I requested.
但來到這里的人卻是你
Yet it was you who arrived on our shores.
別讓我為自己的第二選擇后悔
Do not make me regret settling for my second choice.
奧登上尉
Captain Alden.
真巧
How fortuitous.
我正打算把這個放在你的門階上呢
I was just about to set this on your doorstep.
我就不賣關子了
I'll spare you the mystery.
明晚會為你舉辦一個招待會
It's a reception tomorrow evening in your honor.
招待會
A reception?
不  沒有必要
No. That's not necessary.
已經定了  你現在是行政委員了
But it is. You're a selectman now.
出于私心  這也是修復我們關系的機會
And, on a more personal note, a chance to make amends
自打你回來  我表現得似乎不甚友好
for my less-than-hospitable behavior since your return.
你能確定出席嗎
Can we trust you'll be in attendance?
不好意思  治安官
Excuse me, Magistrate.
霍克中尉
Lieutenant Hooke.
約翰·奧登
John Alden.
你就這么問候
Now, is this any way to greet the man
把你從野蠻人手里救出來的人嗎
who saved you from those savages?
你來這里做什么
What the hell are you doing here?
做生意  上尉
Business, Captain.
港口有艘船  上面載有我的貨物
There is a vessel in port on which I have cargo.
在檢疫結束之前
And until the quarantine is lifted,
我是被困在這個巫師小鎮了
I am marooned here in your little witch town.
我們說好的  再簡單不過了
We had a deal, and it was a simple one...
我不想再見到你
that I was never to set eyes on you again.
沒錯  你不必擔心
Yes. Well, you needn't worry.
我們都不再是打仗時的樣子了
We're not the same men we were in the war.
不過
But...
你確實能行個方便讓我早點離開
There is something you could do to hasten my departure.
什么事
What is that?
戰時你提到的那個女孩  瑪麗·沃科特
The girl you spoke of in battle... Mary Wolcott.
現在她是瑪麗·西布里了  是吧
Although she's Mary Sibley now, isn't she?
如果將我引薦給她  一定能...
An introduction with her would certain...
你離瑪麗遠點
You stay away from Mary.
否則如何  約翰
Or what, John?
你會怎么做
What will you do?
做我上次就該做的事
What I should have done last time.
小心點  上尉
Now, careful, Captain.
一個人撂下狠話之前
Before a man makes threats,
應該先掂量所面臨的風險
he should take stock of what he risks...
除非你不介意我告訴塞勒姆的人們
unless you do not mind me telling the good people of Salem
約翰·奧登到底是個什么樣的人
just who John Alden really is...
他并非所標榜的錚錚男兒  更不是戰斗英雄
neither the man nor the war hero he purports to be.
我要你盡快把生意了結了
I want you to finish your business with all due haste,
之后不管你坐車騎馬或者乘船  我要你離開
and then by coach or by steed or by ship, I want you gone.
我向你保證
You have my word.
西布里先生的喂食
Mr. Sibley's feeding will have to wait
得等我從招待會上回來了
until I return from the reception.
不好意思
Excuse me.
西布里夫人
Mrs. Sibley.
你是哪位
And you are?
我是霍克  威廉·霍克
I'm Hooke... William Hooke.
原諒我的魯莽   我只是在想
Forgive my boldness, but I wondered
或許可以和您談談滯留在港口的船只
if I might speak to you of your ship detained in port.
你多半也聽說了  它得接受檢疫
As you've doubtless heard, it's under quarantine.
不必麻煩了
Well, 'tis no bother.
我只想登船取回我的貨物
I merely mean to board the vessel and retrieve my cargo.
冒著被感染甚至更嚴重的風險嗎
And risk infection? Or worse?
那想必是很寶貴的貨物了  霍克先生
Well, this must be very valuable cargo, Mr. Hooke.
抱歉
Sorry.
任何人不得登船
No one's permitted on board.
或許西布里先生
Well, perhaps Mr. Sibley
會更明理一些呢
will be more open to reason.
我能向你保證  霍克先生
I can assure you, Mr. Hooke,
我丈夫與我對所有事務的看法都是一致的
my husband and I are of one mind on all matters.
晚安
Good evening.
梅西  如果你能聽見  我懇求你
Mercy, if you can hear me, I beseech you,
告訴我附身于你
speak to me the name
意欲報復的惡靈到底是誰
of the vengeful spirit that possesses you.
她經歷的苦難還不夠嗎
Hasn't she suffered enough?
因此我才要想辦法結束她的苦難
Which is why I seek to end her suffering...
將她從惡魔手中解救出來
by freeing her from the demon inside.
麥哲牧師
Reverend Mather?
龍牙草
Agrimony?
藥劑師的主意
The...apothecary's suggestion.
沒有藥用價值的草藥
A herb with no medicinal value.
-常用于驅魔術 -沒錯
- Used historically in exorcisms. - Mmm.
她醒了
She wakes.
梅西
Mercy?
能聽到我說話嗎
Can you hear me?
是的  牧師
Yes, reverend.
她看起來好多了
She looks well.
眼神清澈
Eyes clear.
體溫也很正常
Skin temperate to the touch.
感謝上帝
Bless God.
天哪
My God.
這是怎么一回事
What is this?
理發師給她做了一次放血療法
The Barber bled her humors.
她的傷口還沒好
She hasn't sufficient time to heal.
安
Anne.
見到你真是意外之喜
What a lovely surprise.
我還以為今晚只有行政委員會出席呢
I anticipated only members of the board.
我說服了父親讓我來的
Oh, I convinced my father to let me attend.
如今在塞勒姆沒有絞刑架和憤怒人群的集會
One can't pass up the rare gathering in Salem
可是越來越少了  我怎么會錯過呢
that doesn't involve a noose and an angry mob.
-很漂亮吧  不是嗎  -當然
- Beautiful, isn't it? - Mm.
是我父親送的
A gift from my father.
我能看看嗎
May I?
精美至極
Exquisite.
我先失陪一陣
If you'll excuse me...
我剛剛還在擔心
And here I feared the guest of honor
咱們今晚宴會的主角不會到場呢
wasn't going to make an appearance at his own party.
我擲了個硬幣
Well, I flipped a coin.
-正面朝上  我就待家里  -如果是背面呢
- Heads, I stay home. - And tails?
我會再扔一次  祈禱這一次是正面
I flip again and pray for heads.
可惜仍不走運
No such luck.
我想你會發現  或許你與這些委員會同伴們
Well, I think you'll find that you have more common ground
有比你想象中更多的共同之處
with your fellow board members than you would have expected.
難道他們也認為塞勒姆已經陷入瘋狂了嗎
Oh. They think salem's gone mad, too?
請隨意  好嗎
Enjoy yourself, huh?
奧登上尉
Captain Alden.
真高興看到你還活著
How nice to see you amongst the living --
打個比方
so to speak.
纈草根
Valerian root?
你已經不擇手段到使用獵人的那些粗劣工具了嗎
You've resorted to the coarse tools of the hunters.
是的  很遺憾
Yes. Well, sadly,
如今我無法再置我至親的安全而不顧
I can no longer take the safety of my loved ones for granted.
很明顯  塞勒姆里有些人
Apparently, there are those in Salem
會品行低劣到對孩子下手
who are not above threatening the lives of children.
她可不是孩子  治安官
She's no child, magistrate.
至少
Certainly not,
從她對約翰·奧登的愛慕之意便可看出
judging by the way she lusts for John Alden.
西布里夫人
Mrs. Sibley.
我一有結果便立刻來通知您了
I came straightaway with news.
梅西·路易絲已經擺脫了她的控制者
Mercy Lewis is free of her possessor.
你確定
You're certain?
我的檢查很詳盡
My exam was thorough.
在她體內我再找不到一絲惡魔殘留的證據
I could glean no remaining evidence of the demon inside.
那真是萬幸啊
How serendipitous.
或許并不只是好運這么簡單
Perhaps beyond good fortune.
這表示巫師的力量正在消退
This is evidence of the witches' waning strength
他們的恐懼正在加深
or waxing fear --
正說明我們的反抗行動起了作用
A testament to the potency of our resistance.
恕我無知  牧師
Forgive me, uh, Reverend,
對于這些事情我知之甚少
As I am but a layman in these matters,
但她又是如何逃出撒旦魔爪的呢
but how did she free herself from satan's grasp?
我發現了龍芽草的痕跡
I detected traces of agrimony,
還有那女孩腹部的一條傷口
as well as an incision in the girl's abdomen,
因此我推測一定是有人對她施行了驅魔術
leading to my supposition that an exorcism had been performed.
驅魔術
An exorcism?
在塞勒姆里有人進行著天主教的儀式
A catholic ritual performed in Salem,
你居然還膽敢聲稱這是好消息
and you have the audacity to present this as good news?
你知道在塞勒姆
Do you know what salem abhors
比巫師更令人憎惡的是什么嗎  牧師
even more than a witch, Reverend?
那就是天主教徒
A catholic.
而如今在你的監視之下
Yet under your most watchful eye,
兩種惡行卻大行其道
you've now allowed both to flourish.
為什么會這樣  牧師
When could this have happened, Reverend --
你是被酒精還是妓女給蒙蔽了理智
When you were distracted by drink or by whores?
西布里夫人
Mrs. Sibley --
用異教徒取代惡魔根本算不上勝利
Replacing demons with heathens is no victory.
看起來就算你成功解決了問題  牧師
Seems even when you succeed, reverend,
你仍能找到法子失敗
you find a way to fail.
如今戰爭一觸即發
We live in a time of war,
敵人就隱藏在我們身邊
our enemies hidden among us.
此時此刻  我們正需要
And so there could be no better time than this
一位新的盟友加入
to welcome a new ally in our fight
來共同對抗威脅小鎮的黑暗勢力
against the dark forces that threaten our town.
在戰爭英雄面前  巫師不足為懼
Witches will be no match for a war hero.
歡迎我們行政委員會的最新成員
The newest member of our board of selectmen --
約翰·奧登上尉
Captain John Alden.
如果巫師并不是普通人呢
What if the witches were not the common folk?
不是以設陷阱為生的獵人  也不是助產的婦女
Not those who trapped our food nor birthed our babies?
如果巫師是那些得到我們信任的領導者呢
What if the witches were those we've entrusted to lead?
或許  是我們最尊貴的委員會成員之一
A member, perhaps, of our most esteemed board?
至少  我希望不是
Well, I hope not,
因為如今  我也是你們的一員了
'cause I'm one of you now.
我相信  如果我們攜手
And, together, I trust
定能終結侵蝕這個小鎮的禍害
we will end the scourge that blights this town.
麥哲牧師
Reverend Mather.
我很抱歉  格里安娜
I'm sorry, Gloriana --
安布里小姐
Miss Embry --
但今天真是非常忙碌的一天
But it has been a very trying day,
而且我還未開始準備明天的布道
and I have not yet begun to prepare tomorrow's sermon.
我只是想謝謝你
I simply wish to thank you --
昨天在大庭廣眾之下
For showing me the depth of your care
讓我看到了你的深切關心
yesterday in the public house.
也謝謝您  安布里小姐
And so you have, Miss Embry.
但我向您保證
Though I assure you that separating you
我趕走那纏著您的人渣僅僅出于道義
from that unsavory character was a mere act of charity.
道義
Charity?
以及憐憫
So, too, pity.
憐憫和道義
Pity and charity?
恐怕正是
I'm afraid.
與感覺無關嗎
And it had nothing to do with feeling?
與我對上帝的
Not beyond the feeling
所有苦難子民的感情無異
I possess for any of God's needy creatures...
就像對饑餓的孩子
A hungry child...
或是受傷的動物一樣
A wounded animal.
對妓女也一樣
A whore?
格里安...
Glori...
安布里小姐  你知道我憎恨那樣的字眼
Miss Embry, you know I detest such words.
但在上帝面前
But in the house of the lord,
我們不能有所欺騙
There can be no deceit.
這不正是你一直在傳播的嗎
Isn't that what you preach?
妓女就是妓女
That a whore is a whore?
但我卻不會用"憐憫"
Just as one would never say "Pity"
來掩飾"熱情"
when they meant "Passion"...
用"道義"來粉飾"妒忌"
"Charity" When they meant "Envy."
妒忌
Envy?
就是當你看到其他男人親吻我
At the thought of another man's mouth on mine,
軀體緊緊地貼著我
His body pressed against mine...
下體進入我體內時的那感覺
His loins enveloped in mine.
上帝啊  請原諒她的不敬
Lord, forgive her impiety.
這是你在我體內進出時
Is that the same lord that you invoke from my bed
在我床上呼喚的那位上帝嗎
as you thrust in and out of me?
是我的唇舌在你胸口和股間游走時
The same lord that you thank
你感謝的那位上帝嗎
as my tongue traces down your chest or up your thigh?
是我向他祈禱
That same lord to which I pray
你回來的許諾不再落空的那位上帝嗎
that your promise to return will never be an empty one?
格里安娜  你不能待在這里
Gloriana, you mustn't be here.
否則如何
Or what?
在上帝的處所  你能怎么樣
What will you do here... in the house of the lord?
柯頓  柯頓
Cot.. Cot...
不  別這樣
No. Please.
西布里先生
Mr. Sibley.
我叫霍克  威廉·霍克
My name is Hooke... William Hooke.
您泊在港口的船上有我的貨物
And I have cargo on your frigate detained in port.
可您夫人卻拒絕解除隔離
Yet your wife refuses to lift the quarantine.
雖然  西布里夫人的美貌驚為天人
Now, whilst Mrs. Sibley's beauty is beyond dispute,
但哪能讓女人來掌管男人的事業呢
What woman truly grasps the necessities of a man's vocation?
她們...
They...
先生
S-sir...
您已經病得又聾又啞了嗎
Has your illness rendered you deaf and dumb?
我...
I...
女巫
我對自己有點失望  上尉
I'm a bit upset with myself, captain.
何出此言
Why?
我邀請你來我家其實別有動機
I invited you to my home under false pretense.
我想贏得你的信任
In hoping to gain your trust,
很明顯  這么做卻起了相反的作用
I have clearly done the very opposite.
您到底想說什么  治安官
What's your point, magistrate?
也許直接告訴您真相
Perhaps it would have been wiser for me
以及我的真實身份  會更明智
to simply tell you the truth about who and what I am.
那是什么
And what's that?
一個憂心忡忡的父親
A concerned father.
三天前  我女兒被下了咒
Three days ago, my daughter was spelled...
至少我相信是這樣
or so I believe.
可她問起時...
And yet when she asked, you...
我說謊了  是的
I lied... yes.
我怎么能告訴她
How could I let her know that there are those out there
外面有人想傷害她
who wish to do her harm?
你也看到他們是怎么對路易絲的
You see what they've done to the Lewis girl,
她已經瘋了
Her mind no longer her own.
如果我的安就是他們的下一個目標怎么辦
What if my Anne is their next target?
你我有著共同的敵人
You and I have a common enemy...
那些會傷害安和我們所有人的女巫
The witches who would do my Anne and all of us harm.
那她們到底是誰
And who are they?
這仍是個謎團
This remains a mystery.
我必須承認
I must admit, uh...
我低估你了
I underestimated you.
謝謝
Well, thank you.
你比我想象得還更人渣
You are full of far more shit than I thought possible.
也許你沒對安下咒
Maybe you did not spell Anne.
也許你的解釋很誠懇
Maybe your explanations have been genuine.
但我不信
But I don't think so.
我覺得你不是好人
I think you're dirty.
一旦我找到證據  整個塞勒姆也會這么想的
And once I find proof, all of Salem will, too.
他對你提了要求  卻完全沒有躁動的跡象
He requested you, yet shows no signs of agitation.
會變的
That will change.
擅闖民居
Breaking into my home?
你知道在塞勒姆  小偷會有什么下場嗎
Do you know what happens to thieves in Salem?
不知道
No.
但我知道女巫會有什么下場
But I know what happens to witches.
女巫
這是什么
What's this?
也許這問題最好由西布里先生來回答
Perhaps a question best asked of Mr. Sibley.
我丈夫遭受的病痛
My husband's affliction
已經剝奪了他的理智和感覺
Has robbed him of both reason and sense.
而這恰是要管理塞勒姆
And yet are either actually required
最需要的兩樣東西
to point the finger in Salem?
我可不怕威脅  霍克先生
I care not for threats, Mr. Hooke.
我也沒打算威脅你
And I care not to resort to them.
也許  我們可以避免
So, perhaps, we could avoid bringing this note
將這字條提交給行政委員會
to the attention of the board of selectmen.
所以要么同意你登我的船
Grant you access to my ship,
要么面對你最無恥的指控是嗎
or face your most scurrilous accusations?
好
Fine.
半夜時分輪船的守衛會回家
At midnight, the ship's sentry will be sent home,
你可以去拿回你的貨
and you can retrieve your cargo.
現在給我滾
Now out with you.
我的靈感出錯了嗎
Does my sense betray me?
他能破壞你的計劃  我們的計劃
He could undo you! All of us!
梅西也可以
And so could Mercy.
靈獸從她身上脫離了
The familiar has been cut from her.
怎么會
How?
通過驅魔術
An exorcism --
毫無疑問是她的傻瓜父親干的
performed by her dolt of a father, no doubt.
我們必須用新的代替
So we must replace it.
如今她怎么會再次接受呢
And yet why would she accept it a second time?
她不會
She wouldn't,
除非我們能觸動
unless there is some part of the girl
那個女孩的某種情感
to which we can appeal.
哪種情感
And what part is that?
就是你曾經觸動過我的那個部分
The same part you once touched in me --
她內心深處對更好的生活的小小憧憬
the deep, small piece of her that longs for a better life.
那你得快點行動
You must move quickly, then.
我會一個人對付霍克先生
I, alone, will take charge of Mr. Hooke.
但是緹圖芭
But, Tituba...
如今事態嚴峻
These are perilous times.
千萬不能讓任何人抓著我們的把柄
No blood must lead back to our door.
明白嗎
Do you understand?
完全了解
Perfectly.
要是我早知道你是約翰·奧登的朋友
Had I known you were a friend of John Alden's,
我會另找其他送貨員
I would have found another courier.
我向你擔保我們不是朋友
I can assure you, we are not friends.
你要是知道那人的真面目
If you knew the truth of the man,
你這么譴責我之前就會三思了
You would rethink such an accusation.
什么真面目
And what truth is that?
無論如何
In any case,
阻礙已除
the impediment has been removed.
半夜包裹就是你的了
The package shall be yours by midnight.
你沒有向她透露我的名字吧
You did not speak my name to her?
我遵囑行事
I did as instructed.
不過我還是禁不住在想  那個包裹
But, still, I can't help but wonder -- this parcel --
你已得到豐厚報酬  其他不必多想
You have been paid well not to wonder,
霍克先生
Mr. Hooke.
梅西
Mercy.
離我遠點
Leave me.
我不會離開的
I won't leave you.
我不能
I can't.
你需要我
You need me.
騙子
You're a liar.
我不需要你
I don't need you.
我附身于你的時候
When you resist me,
你指出一個僅你可見的魔鬼的時候
When you point at a demon that only you can see,
他們做了什么
What do they do?
他們剪去你的頭發
They shave your locks.
為你可憐的靈魂哭泣
They weep for your wretched soul.
走開  快走開
Go away! Go!
沒有我  你只是個
Without me, you are but a girl,
軟弱又平凡的女孩
weak and ordinary.
但是讓我附身于你
But with me inside you, you are...
你就會無所不能
omnipotent.
別哭了
Hush, now.
別給他們理由可憐你
Give them no cause to pity you.
讓他們只能敬畏你
Give them only reason to fear you.
不  不要
No! No!
張嘴  孩子
Open, girl.
張嘴吧
Open your mouth.
這就對了
Yes.
就像那樣
Just like that.
它選擇了你成為它地球上的使者
He has chosen you to be his vessel on earth.
能為它服務
There is no greater honor
是至高榮耀
than to be in his service.
怎么了  怎么了
What? What?
怎么回事  怎么回事
What? What? What?
她是我的
She is mine.
緹圖芭
Tituba?
瑪麗出事了
Mary is in trouble.
我只是個仆人  上尉
I am but a servant, captain,
沒有權利如此冒犯
unentitled to such an intrusion.
到底是什么事
What is it?
恐怕您和我的女主人
I fear you and my mistress
有一個共同的敵人
share a common adversary --
霍克先生
Mr. Hooke.
你怎么知道他
How did you know that he --
我看見您在鎮中心外的大雜院里和他爭執
I saw you quarreling in the warren off the square.
他要求進入我女主人的船
He demands access to my mistress' ship.
為什么
Why?
是像他說的那樣只為找個沒有價值的包裹
To retrieve some worthless parcel, as he claims?
還是他包藏禍心
Or does he harbor darker intent?
他計劃打劫她
He plans to rob her.
我的女主人也如此擔心
So my mistress fears.
西布里夫人為什么準許他登船呢
Why did Mrs. Sibley allow him to board that vessel?
她別無選擇
He left her no choice.
他以散播關于我女主人
He threatened to spread false rumor of an affair --
和你有染的虛假消息來要挾  上尉
with you, captain.
她本想與他理論  但是
She sought to reason with him, but --
他并不是個講理的人
He is not a man that responds to reason.
西布里夫人要是知道我找你一定會責罵我
Mrs. Sibley would lash me if she knew I had come,
但是我擔心霍克先生會毀了她
but I fear Mr. Hooke will be her ruin.
除非
Unless --
說吧  姑娘
Speak, girl.
除非有人能阻止他
Unless there be a man who desires to stop him.
喬治·西布里
包裹4769
你喜歡他  是嗎
You have feelings for him, don't you?
他是誰
"Him"?
一定要我說出他的名字嗎
Must I say his name?
這對今晚所有在場的人來說不是顯而易見嗎
Was it not obvious to all who were present this evening?
這不是一個女人應有的特權嗎
Is it not a woman's prerogative
選擇自己喜歡的男人
to choose which man she fancies?
是沒錯
It is.
就像這也是父親的特權
Just as it is a father's prerogative
去保護他女兒的心
to protect his daughter's heart
不被那些可能會傷害她的人接近
from those he feels will do it harm.
譬如約翰·奧登
John Alden, for instance.
你為什么要這么說
Why do you say this?
就因為他不像塞勒姆那些毛躁的
Because he doesn't curry your favor,
年輕人一樣對你阿諛奉承嗎
like every other twitchy young man in Salem?
不  這不是原因
No. That is not it.
他永遠都是屬于瑪麗·西布里
How could he ever be yours truly
又怎能成為你的摯愛
when he always was and always will be Mary Sibley's?
他們的歷史不是個秘密
Their history is no secret.
但也僅此而已  是個歷史
But it is just that -- history.
她是個已婚的女人了
She is a married woman now.
你真的以為瑪麗·西布里會站在一旁
And do you suppose Mary Sibley will idly stand by
看著你占據她認為屬于自己
while you claim that which she rightfully considers
的東西嗎
to be her own?
你怕她  父親
You fear her, father.
我不怕
I do not.
你只是個孩子  你不明白
You are but a child. You don't understand.
一個孩子
A child?
不久前  你還同意我是個女人
A moment ago, you agreed I was a woman.
這沒什么可爭論的
It's not for debate.
-到底誰說了算  -我說了算
- By whose command? - By mine!
你的父親
Your father!
你的所有者和主人
Your lord and master!
我禁止你與奧登上尉今后再有任何來往
I forbid you to have further contact with captain Alden!
不然呢
Or what?
我會受到怎樣的懲罰
What punishment awaits me?
你會奪走我的生命嗎  就像你對敵人一般
Will you crush the life from me, as you do your enemies?
或者僅僅是我的靈魂
Or just my spirit,
像你對所愛之人做的一樣
as you do those you love?
閉嘴
Quiet!
不準再說了
Not one word more!
把那放下
Put it down.
不
No.
這個箱子屬于我
This parcel belongs to me.
這權利連瑪麗·西布里也無法奪走
A claim that even Mary Sibley cannot dispute.
我不是代表她來的
I'm not here on her behalf.
現在  把它放下
Now put it down.
問問你自己  上尉
Ask yourself, captain...
這真的值得嗎
Is it really worth it?
什么
What?
解決老恩怨的代價
The cost of settling old scores.
如果被治安官發現你所做的事情
What would be the charge
你覺得會被判什么罪
if the magistrate knew what you did?
謀殺
Murder?
叛國
Treason?
二者皆有
Both?
你知道那天發生了什么
You know what happened that day.
是的
Yes.
我看著你潑灑無辜的鮮血
I watched you spill innocent blood.
沒有一絲后悔與憐憫
Without regret or remorse.
多少人像畜牲一般被屠殺
Men slaughtered like animals.
所有人  都死了
All of them -- dead.
不是所有人
Not all of them.
我們有過交易  霍克先生
We had a deal, Mr. Hooke --
那天你跪在地上求饒
The day you fell to your knees and begged for your life
說如果我放你一條生路
that should I let you live,
你將不會再出現在我面前
we would never cross paths again.
你沒有遵守約定
You didn't hold up your end.
好好想清楚  上尉
Now, think this through, captain.
我當然有
Oh, I have --
很詳細地想過
thoroughly.
那天我唯一后悔的就是沒有趕盡殺絕
And the only life I lament that day was the one I spared.
你該遵守約定的  霍克先生
A man should keep his promises, Mr. Hooke.
所以  你打算在這里割了我的喉
So you're...just going to slit my throat here,
像那些印第安野蠻人一樣
like some yellow horse?
不
No.
西布里夫人
Mrs. Sibley.
看來今晚大家似乎都為失眠而困擾
Sleeplessness seems to be epidemic this evening.
你還記得
Do you remember
我們上一次
the last time we spoke,
在墓地陰影中的談話嗎
in the shadow of the graveyard?
當然記得
Of course.
我們做出的約定
The promises we made?
你會在一年內回來
You would return within a year.
而你將屏息等待
And you would breathlessly wait.
那些都是謊言嗎
Were they lies?
不是
No.
這些是愿望
They were wishes.
不諳世事的人許下的愿望
Made by those that knew nothing of the world.
現在呢
And now?
我們明白了
We know.
我們的心之所向往往卻與生存所需
What we desire and what we must do to survive
背道而馳
are often at odds.
很晚了  上尉
It's, uh, late, captain.
是很晚了
It is.
我就寢時間早過了
Long past my bedtime.
祝你好夢  瑪麗
I wish you sweet dreams, Mary.
或許這已經是一場美夢了
Perhaps they've already begun.
我知道你是什么東西
I know what you are.